# **CURRICULUM VITAE**



# Dr. Najlaa Saadi Ismael

# 🎉 Amman, Jordan

6

+962-777414338 +962-64799000 Ext.2641



nsaadi@philadelphia.edu.jo dr.najlaasaadi@yahoo.com



http://www.philadelphia.edu.jo/acade mics/nsaadi/



https://drnajlaa.github.io/

## **SUMMARY**

I am Assistant Professor; I have extensive experience in research and academic teaching at the College of Medicine and Faculty of Pharmacy. I have a versed in formulating research goals, researching methods and testing parameters, analyzing data, and generating detailed reports. My main research interests include research related to various Clinical Pharmacological field.

#### Languages:

• English: Full Professional proficiency.

Arabic: Native Proficiency

## **Degrees (Qualifications):**

- 1. PhD in Pharmacology, College of Medicine, University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq.
- 2. M. Sc in Pharmacology, College of Medicine, University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq.
- 3. B. Sc. (Dental Surgery), College of Dentistry, University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq.

#### **Educational Information:**

#### Ph.D. Thesis

Comparative Effects of Telmisartan versus Valsartan on Serum Leptin and Homeostatic Model Assessment of Insulin Resistance in Hypertensive Patients with Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus.

#### Ms.C. Thesis

Monitoring of Some Liver Function Tests During Ranitidine and Omeprazole Therapy.

## **Teaching Experience:**

- 1. Teaching of the Pharmacology 1, Pharmacology 2 & Pharmacology 3 in Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Philadelphia, Amman, Jordan. (2015 until now).
- 2. Teaching of the Pharmacology for 3<sup>rd</sup> year students in the College of Medicine, University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq. (10years).
- 3. Teaching of the practical Pharmacology (laboratory) for 3<sup>rd</sup> year students in the College of Medicine, University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq.

## Past Jobs (Occupation):

- 1. Coordinator of Pharmacology, Toxicology and Therapeutics in the Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Philadelphia, Amman, Jordan. (2016- 2018).
- 2. Assistant Professor, in the Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Philadelphia, Amman, Jordan. (2015 until now).
- 3. Lecturer in Department of Pharmacology, College of Medicine, University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq. (10 years).
- 4. Director of Research and Development, Planning and Informatics department in the College of Medicine, University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq. (3 years).

## **Experiences, Certificates and Professional Courses:**

- 1. Participation in the Session of Laboratory Teaching Styles, organized by the Center of Developing Teaching Methodology & University Training for the University of Mosul Lecturers.
- 2. Participation in the Teaching Methodology Session, organized by the Center of Developing Teaching Methodology & University Training for the Scientific Promotion for the University of Mosul Lecturers.
- 3. Participation in the Session Organized by the Computer & Internet Center for the Efficiency of the Computer for Graduate Students for the University of Mosul.
- 4. Participation in the session organized by UNICEF about the breastfeeding in Baghdad.
- 5. Participation in the training workshop: Ethical Issues for research, Philadelphia University, Amman/Jordan
- 6. Participation in the PhD Applicant workshop (Queens university Belfast 2018)
- 7. Participation in the Google form and Google drive workshop , Philadelphia University, Amman/ Jordan
- 8. Participation in many medical and pharmaceutical conferences and Symposiums.
- 9. Ability of analyzing the data by Statistical Package for Social Sciences (SPSS) for medical research.
- 10. Teaching with use up-to-date instructional technology.

#### **Professional & Scientific Committees**

- 1. Committee member of Quality Assurance, Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Philadelphia, Amman, Jordan
- 2. Committee member of Academic Advising in the Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Philadelphia, Amman, Jordan
- 3. Member of the Community Committee at the Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Philadelphia, Amman, Jordan
- 4. Committee member of the exams in the College of Medicine, University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq.
- 5. Committee member of the Curriculum Development for Department of Pharmacology in the College of Medicine, University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq.
- 6. Committee Member of the Collection to Curriculums for all Departments of College of Medicine in the University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq.

#### **RESEARCHES**

#### **Published Research**

- 1. Book Chapter 12: Quality Control and Testing Evaluation of Pharmaceutical Aerosols. (*Drug Delivery systems-* 1<sup>st</sup> *Edition, Published date:* 1<sup>st</sup> *November* 2019).
- 2. The effect of using combined oral ethinyl estradiol and levonorgestrel in the resolution of menstrual pattern disorder and functional ovarian cyst. (Ann Coll Med Mosul Volume: 41, No.2, 2019).
- 3. Comparative Effects of Telmisartan versus Valsartan on HOMA-IR in type2 Diabetes Mellitus Patients with Hypertension. (*Indian Journal of Applied Research Volume:* 4, Issue: 1, Jan 2014).
- 4. Comparative Effects of Telmisartan versus Valsartan on serum Leptin level, in hypertensive type2 Diabetes Mellitus patients. (*Iraqi journal of pharmacy Volume:* 14, No.1, 2014).
- 5. Effects of Glibenclamide vs Metformin on serum uric acid levels in patients with type-2 diabetes mellitus. (*Iraqi journal of pharmacy Volume: 11, No.1, 2011*).
- 6. Human Recombinant Erythropoietin in the Treatment of Anemia of Patients with Chronic Renal Failure. (MJBU, Volume: 27, No.1, 2009).

## **Accepted Researches for Publication:**

7. Efficacy of Follitropin-a (Gonal-F) versus Follitropin —b (Puregon) for controlled ovarian stimulation in women undergoing IVF. (Accepted for publication in International Journal of Pharmaceutical Quality Assurance, date for publication volume: 11, No.2 to get release in April-Jun 2020).

#### **Submitted Researches for Publication:**

- 8. Book Chapter: Pharmacology of Neuropeptides (Substance P, Vasoactive Intestinal Peptides (Vip), Neuropeptide Y, Calcitonin Peptidesand Others) And Their Receptors.
- 9. Comparative study of non-pregnant women with Perinatal Depression, prevalence, suicidal attempt and factors participating in Jordanian woman.

## The Researches Which Still in Performance Stages

- 10. Comparative effects of metformin and sodium-glucose cotransporter 2(SGLT2) inhibitors on glycemic control, kidney function in type2 Diabetes Mellitus
- 11. Gynecological Problem and Vitamin D Deficiency.
- 12. The study of immunogenicity, stability and safety of Vaccine against Clostridium perfringens Alpha Toxins.
- 13. Efficacy of Follitropin-a versus Follitropin -b for controlled ovarian stimulation.